

FAISAL SAEED

DIGITAL DESIGN ENGINEER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Digital Design Engineer specialized in RTL design and verification methodologies. Actively contributes to advanced System-on-Chip (SoC) designs, integrating technologies like AMBA protocols, with a future orientation toward DDR memory, controller, and DDR PHY. Meticulous attention to detail and commitment to excellence ensure high-performance designs.

CONTACT INFO



+92-3327393496



faisalsaeedawan20@gmail.com



https://faisalawan11.github.io/Portf



https://www.linkedin.com/in/fai sal-saeed-02334bab/

Design Engineer

COMIRA SOLUTIONS

EXPERIENCE

TRAINEE ENGINEER **COMIRA SOLUTIONS**

APR 2023- PRESENT

OCT 2022- MAR 2023

• Collaborating with CoMira team on SoC development

· Developed strong experties in Verilog HDL for efficcient

• Developed a UVM testbench for integrating an ALU and

hardware design and verification, employing best

practices with industry standards

synchronous FIFO modules

- Working on LaTex for the documentation of SoC
- Writing C++ testbench for SoC development. This includes generating test cases, applying stimuli, and checking the expected outputs

EXPERTISE

- Verilog/System verilog
- Universal Verification Methodology(UVM)
- · Shell scripting
- Git

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Verilator
- QuestaSim

CERTIFICATION

• Chip Design Verification Essentials training certification from NUST University

EDUCATION

BACHELOR IN INDUSTRIAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING NED UNIVERSITY | 2011-2015

APPRENTICESHIP IN B2/AVIONICS PAKISTAN INTERNATIONAL AIRLINES | 2016-2018

MASTERS IN ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING

GHULAM ISHAQ KHAN INSTITUTE OF ENGINEERING SCIENCES AND TECHNOLOGY | 2020-2023